<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Evert Timberg</title>
    <link>https://everttimberg.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Evert Timberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 20:49:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://everttimberg.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Management and Ad Blocking</title>
      <link>https://everttimberg.io/post/family-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 20:49:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://everttimberg.io/post/family-tech/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of tools that can make browsing safer and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-pass&#34;&gt;Last Pass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lastpass.com/&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; is a program that you install into your browser. It saves your passwords so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to remember them. To install simply click the &amp;ldquo;Get LastPass Free&amp;rdquo; button and follow the instructions. As part of the installation process, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to create an account and a master password. Keep this master password safe, since if you lose it you will lose access to all the saved passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you sign in to LastPass on another computer, all your passwords will be synced so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to remember them. The free LastPass version will not sync your passwords to a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Once you have LastPass installed, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a redicon in your toolbar like the one in the image below. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve signed in, this icon will allow you to find passwords that have been saved in your vault.
&lt;image class=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://everttimberg.io/images/family-tech/last-pass-toolbar-icon.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ublock-origin&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm?hl=en&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; is a program that blocks ads from running in your browser. Blocking ads means that websites will load faster, your browsing habits won&amp;rsquo;t be tracked by a third party, and it reduces the chances of getting malware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Installing it is easy in Chrome. All you have to do is click the link to add it as an extension. From then on it should be activated and blocking ads. You can deactivate it in the future by going to &lt;code&gt;chrome://extensions&lt;/code&gt; in a browsers tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;incognito-mode&#34;&gt;Incognito Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome has a mode to hide your history and cookies. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95464?source=gsearch&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; has some great details on how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The case study I gave is airline tickes. Airline websites will store a cookie on your computer to keep track of which flights you&amp;rsquo;ve viewed. When you return to the site, the price displayed will be higher than before. Using incognito mode (and closing it between visits to the site) will prevent this behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on Chart.js in 2016</title>
      <link>https://everttimberg.io/post/new-year-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 18:45:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://everttimberg.io/post/new-year-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;script src=&#34;https://everttimberg.io/js/Chart.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chart.js has had an incredible last year. In April, we successfully launched v2.0 culminating a year and a half of hard work. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of smaller releases after that, each of which has helped build on the incredible interactivity that comes standard in v2. We also released our first new chart type in a long time; the horizontal bar chart. This was a long sought request, that fit in well with the work we did in v2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Coupled with this work, we saw a dramatic increase in use this year, with monthly NPM installs going from ~20k to over 200k per month. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing and humbling to see so many users choosing Chart.js for their projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chart-container&#34;&gt;
	&lt;canvas id=&#34;chartjs-monthly-downloads&#34; class=&#34;extra-large-chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
var ctx = document.getElementById(&#34;chartjs-monthly-downloads&#34;).getContext(&#39;2d&#39;);
var chartInstance = new Chart(ctx, 
{
    type: &#39;line&#39;,
    data: {
        labels: [&#39;Jan 2015&#39;, &#39;Feb 2015&#39;, &#39;Mar 2015&#39;, &#39;Apr 2015&#39;, &#39;May 2015&#39;, &#39;Jun 2015&#39;, &#39;Jul 2015&#39;, &#39;Aug 2015&#39;, &#39;Sep 2015&#39;, &#39;Oct 2015&#39;, &#39;Nov 2015&#39;, &#39;Dec 2015&#39;, &#39;Jan 2016&#39;, &#39;Feb 2016&#39;, &#39;Mar 2016&#39;, &#39;Apr 2016&#39;, &#39;May 2016&#39;, &#39;Jun 2016&#39;, &#39;Jul 2016&#39;, &#39;Aug 2016&#39;, &#39;Sep 2016&#39;, &#39;Oct 2016&#39;, &#39;Nov 2016&#39;, &#39;Dec 2016&#39;],
        datasets: [{
            data: [826, 1240, 2156, 3231, 4050, 5802, 6817, 7029, 8251, 10870, 13887, 17470, 20498, 27370, 42472, 61385, 70688, 79499, 86129, 113562, 135716, 181799, 204399, 201846],
            label: &#39;Chart.js NPM Installs&#39;,
            borderColor: &#39;#36A2EB&#39;,
            pointBackgroundColor: &#39;#36A2EB&#39;,
            backgroundColor: &#39;rgba(54,162,235, 0.4)&#39;,
            fill: false
        }]
    },
    options: {
        title: {
            display: true,
            text: &#39;Chart.js Monthly Installs&#39;
        },
        legend: {
            display: false
        },
        tooltips: {
            callbacks: {
                label: function(tooltipItem, data) {
                    var ds = data.datasets[tooltipItem.datasetIndex];
                    var datasetLabel = ds.label;
                    return datasetLabel + &#34;: &#34; + ds.data[tooltipItem.index].toLocaleString();
                }
            }
        }
    }
}
);
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The data in the above chart is from &lt;a href=&#34;https://npm-stat.com/charts.html?package=Chart.js&amp;amp;from=2015-01-01&amp;amp;to=2016-12-31&#34;&gt;NPM Stat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2017-roadmap&#34;&gt;2017 Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In 2017, we are committed to working on improving the ability to run Chart.js in an environment other than the browser. In version 2.5, we will have factored out the browser specific events into a removable piece known as a &lt;code&gt;platform&lt;/code&gt;. With this change, it will be possible to create a build that runs in a JavaScript environment that does not have the DOM APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We have also committed to improving our documentation. We are working on creating auto-generated documentation so that we can have the latest dev docs auto update when new commits are added. This will allow us to be more responsive to user feedback and ensure timely corrections when the docs have errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Overall, 2017 is shaping up to be a great year for Chart.js. Have a safe and happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this Site</title>
      <link>https://everttimberg.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://everttimberg.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal site. I wrote the site using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator written in Go. It&amp;rsquo;s been a great introduction to the Go template language. Hosting is done via static files published to Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I tried to make the site depend on as little JavaScript as possible. The only necessary JS is used to trigger the mobile menu view. Everything else was written using pure CSS and media queries. I used Sass to compile the CSS. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mastastealth/sass-flex-mixin&#34;&gt;sass flex mixin&lt;/a&gt; was particularly helpful for generating the flexbox styling used in the photo albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/gulp-image-resize&#34;&gt;gulp-image-resize&lt;/a&gt; in a gulp task to automatically generate thumbnails for images. This greatly improved page performance and kept the process relatively pain free. In the future, I will likely add automatic watermarking as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>