<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Evert Timberg</title>
    <link>https://everttimberg.io/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Evert Timberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 10:42:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://everttimberg.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Redux</title>
      <link>https://everttimberg.io/blog/thoughts-on-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 10:42:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://everttimberg.io/blog/thoughts-on-redux/</guid>
      <description>Redux is a state management library that is commonly used in React apps. Redux was created in 2015 and almost immediately became a common sight in React apps. This may have been due to the fact that many of the React docs assumed that Redux was installed along with the popularity of boilerplates that included Redux by default. As a result of this, many front-end developers including myself, incorrectly assumed that React had to be used with Redux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular Gradients for the HTML5 Canvas</title>
      <link>https://everttimberg.io/blog/js-circular-gradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 18:19:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://everttimberg.io/blog/js-circular-gradient/</guid>
      <description>Circular gradients are commonly used in pie or doughnut charts to change the colour of segment as the angle around the center of the chart changes. In many non web platforms, the ability to generate these gradients is provided as part of the standard APIs. For example, Android provides a SweepGradient. In the browsers, only Linear and Radial gradients are provided. Thus, if we want to a circular gradient, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to create our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Custom React Hook to Keep State in Query String</title>
      <link>https://everttimberg.io/blog/custom-react-hook-query-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://everttimberg.io/blog/custom-react-hook-query-state/</guid>
      <description>A common problem with many web apps is that it is not easy to share links to another user. This is usually due to the fact that the transient page state is only stored in memory.
I ran into this recently with a page in an app that allowed the user to view a parameter over time. The filter parameters (id, startTime, and endTime) were all stored in the component state and so if the user refreshed the page, all of the previous selection was lost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
